Ben Isenstein

Calgary, AB

403-477-4176

ben.isenstein@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/benisenstein/

Summary

A capable full stack developer with experience in agile software development and entrepreneurship. Five years of transferable experience in extremely fast-paced environments as a freelance musician and composer.

Systems thinker, with experience building reusable software for developer teams. Able to learn quickly, solve problems effectively, and apply new learnings across projects.

Ambitious team member with a passion for clear communication, collaboration, and accountability. Values interpersonal skills, productivity, and cultural competence with all colleagues/clients.

Over ten years of experience in varied environments with an emphasis on giving and receiving mentorship (YMCA, Elizabeth Fry, SAIT Summer Camps, Ottawa Youth Jazz Summit).

Education

Full Stack Developer (Evolve Vocational Program) – InceptionU, Calgary, AB (2021) https://www.inceptionu.com/full-stack-developer-program

"Learn to be a developer, not just code... full-stack application development using the MERN stack as well as non-technical skills including: critical thinking, working in teams, design thinking, and workplace readiness... project-based learning program designed to simulate an agile working environment, and includes daily stand-ups, weekly sprints, and weekly retrospectives."

Bachelor of Music (Jazz Piano Performance, Honors) - University of Toronto, Toronto, ON (2020)

Technical Skills

- Python, AppleScript, Bash, CSS, SCSS, Html, JavaScript
- Git, Github, node.js, NPM, Heroku, webpack, babel
- Agile Development using Trello
- MERN stack
- End-to-end delivery of polished, working features
- RESTful API (Google Maps/Drive/Cloud/OAuth, Open Weather, MongoDB, Express.js)
- Authentication with Passport.js, bcrypt
- Frontend features using React, React-Router, React-Hook-Form, Styled-Components

Web Development Work

Personal Github Homepage

https://github.com/benIsenstein

Grow Calgary - InceptionU project 2

https://growcalgary.herokuapp.com/

Role: Full stack dev

Team: Self-directed team of 4

Timeframe: ~7 weeks

"Grow is a web application offering helpful and easy-to-use tools for gardening beginners, pros, and organizers alike. Users can add their community garden to the app, search for gardens in the city of Calgary, access weather, share best practices via message board, and more."

Taskr - InceptionU project 3

https://taskr-1.herokuapp.com/

Role: Full stack dev

Team: Team of 4 + Scrum Master, Agile Software Development Best-Practices

Timeframe: ~12 weeks

"Household tasks never getting done? Whether forgetting the schedule or not knowing what to do, maintaining a home or managing a few, it can be challenging but we have an answer. Now with TASKr, the recurring home management app, your maintenance tasks are only a click away. Upon creation of an account, you create your digital home with a customizable list of tasks based on industry-recognized standards."

Canada Tax Calculator 2021

https://canada-tax-calculator-2021.herokuapp.com/

Role: Full stack dev

Team: Solo Project, Agile Software Development Best-Practices

Timeframe: ~2 weeks

React-hook-superform

React package developed independently and used extensively in InceptionU project 3

https://www.npmjs.com/package/@benisenstein/react-hook-superform

"Harness the power of react-hook-form and create functional forms in React, FAST."

Professional Development

- "Indigenous Canada" University of Alberta through Coursera (Completion October 2021)
- "2020 Complete Python Bootcamp From Zero to Hero in Python" curated for the 'Udemy for Business' collection (2021)
- "JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures" FreeCodeCamp.org (2021)
- Participant, SEEDS CONNECTIONS program (2014), sponsorship provided by Cenovus Energy

"The CONNECTIONS Program encourages students to be the change they want to see in the world by:

- o expanding awareness of diversity issues and fostering cross-cultural understanding
- o working together to fight ethnocentrism, stereotyping, racism, prejudice & discrimination
- o empowering students to develop & utilize their personal leadership skills to affect positive change
- o connecting with nature and recognizing diverse issues in the environment"

Work Experience

Contractor, Tutor Doctor Calgary (September 2020 – April 2021)

 Providing student-specific academic tutoring to high school students in Math, Science and English. Maintaining communication with families, planning lessons, submitting invoices.

Camps Leader, SAIT Summer Camps (June - August 2018, August 2019)

- Delivered unique, engaging, educational and skill building experiences to youth in grades 4-12 in a safe and fun environment
- Six single-week business-oriented camps: Next Great Entrepreneur, Investment Masters, Corporate Creators, Money Masters, Supply Chain of Command, Advertising Adventures
- 2019 Camps: DramACTic Kids (Drama), Literacy Explorers (creative writing)
- Used exceptional organization, time management, and communication skills in a fast-paced environment
- Worked with children who are neuro-diverse and have varying needs
- Demonstrated a strong ability to manage stressful situations calmly and effectively
- Modelled appropriate behaviors for children and youth

Collaborative Freelance Musician, Calgary/Montreal/Toronto/Ottawa/Italy (2015 – Present)

- Participant, Siena Jazz International Summer Workshop, Italy. July-August 2019
- Member, TD Ottawa Jazz Fest Youth Summit 2019: 9-piece band, all-expenses paid youth residency
- Youth Blues Challenge 2016, High Performance Rodeo One Yellow Rabbit & Alberta Theatre Projects
- Presented by Youth Jazz Canada at The Beaches Jazz Fest and Jazz Bistro, Toronto (2016)
- Presented by Youth Jazz Canada at the REX Jazz & Blues bar, Emmet Ray and Jazz Bistro, Toronto (2017)
- Toronto Undergraduate Jazz Festival September 2016, September 2017, September 2019
- Leader and coordinator of an inter-provincial jazz project at Café Résonance, Montreal (May 2018)
- JazzYYC YouthLab community band 2015-16 season

Marketer, College Pro Painters

May-June 2017

Grew a client base for the owner of a painting franchise by marketing to previous clients and door-to-door

Business Owner/Operator, Flow Custom Kendamas

2012-2014

- Imported over 400 kendamas (Japanese skill toy), resulting in gross sales of ~\$10,000
- Grew a customer base locally to over 100 people
- Promoted community through weekly events, competitions and private functions

Achievements/Awards

- Andrew Alexander Kinghorn Scholarship in Music, University of Toronto Academic Scholarship
- STINGRAY MUSIC Award, 2019 TD Ottawa Jazz Festival Youth Summit
- Bill Wilson Memorial Award In Jazz Studies, , University of Toronto Academic Scholarship
- Alexander Rutherford Scholarship, Alberta Education over 80% academic average for 2014, 2015, 2016
- The Don Buchignani Award, (Outstanding Senior High School Varsity Male Swimmer) Calgary Booster Club, 2016
- Ivy and Len Freeston Arts Scholarship Education Matters
- "3 Year-3 Sport" Award Crescent Heights High School volleyball, swimming, track and field
- Top Academic Honours Crescent Heights High School Jazz 15, 25, 35
- Top Academic Honours Crescent Heights High School Math 30-1

Additional Experience

Youth Mentorship Volunteer, Elizabeth Fry Society of Calgary

Fall 2020 - Present

- Received training in understanding Alberta's criminal justice system, issues of immigration, Indigenous awareness, and mentoring youth dealing with criminal charges.
- Attended meet-and-greets with potential mentees, spent time one-on-one, establishing rapport.